ahml.info 2013-03-06

# Privacy Statement | AHML

The Arlington Heights Memorial Library is strongly committed to protecting the privacy of its online users. The library is supported in protecting the privacy of its users by national and state-level laws, as well as the library's policy 4.001, Privacy and Confidentiality of Patron-Identifiable Records.  

**Type of Information Collected**

Where it is necessary for the library to identify users, it is our goal to gather only the minimum information necessary and to retain that information for only as long as it is needed to complete a particular transaction. This can include IP address, browser type, domain names, access times, and referring web site addresses. Additionally, personally identifiable information may be transmitted in connection with other activities, services, or resources made available on our site.  

**How the Information Is Used**

The information is used by the library for the operation of a service, to maintain quality of a service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of web sites. Any personally identifiable information provided to the library is maintained by and accessible only to the library unless the library explicitly states otherwise. The Arlington Heights Memorial Library does not sell, rent, lease, or otherwise provide its customer lists to third parties.

Although your privacy is very important to us, we may be forced to disclose information to the government or third parties where necessary to comply with law. In addition, in the unlikely event that we need to investigate or resolve problems or inquiries associated with the operation of the library, we may find it necessary to disclose information to parties outside of the library, such as law enforcement or other government officials.  

**Third-Party Web Sites**

The library web site contains links to web sites and resources owned and operated by third parties, including databases and electronic journals, which the library has licensed for the use of patrons. While every attempt is made to include user information protections in license agreements with these third parties, your use of these web sites and resources is not governed by this Privacy Statement. We recommend that you review the privacy policies of any web site that you visit.  

**Security**

The library has taken reasonable measures to safeguard the integrity of its data and prevent unauthorized access to information we maintain. Steps include, but are not limited to, authentication, monitoring, and auditing. Security measures have been integrated into the design, implementation and day-to-day practices of the entire operating environment. These measures are intended to prevent corruption of data, block unknown or unauthorized access to our systems and information, and to provide reasonable protection of private information in our possession. For example, information required when making credit card payments using Ecommerce, is encrypted and transmitted via secure connection to the library's payment center. No security measures, however, can guarantee complete security from unauthorized "hackers."  

**Cookies**

A "cookie" is information that a web site can place on a computer's hard drive to collect information about the user. A cookie records an individual's preferences in using a certain web site. The Arlington Heights Memorial Library does not use any persistent cookies to collect permanent information. The library may use nonpersistent cookies in applications that keep track of a user's session. Nonpersistent cookies are only necessary to maintain session information and are temporary. They are invalidated once a user's session is completed.  

**Acceptance of Terms**

Using the library's web site signifies your acceptance of this Privacy Statement.  
March 1, 2006
